After the simulation is stable, we need to activate the outer layer and the inner layer at the same time to see if the inner layer is unstable.
Recall that we used the fake stitch tool before, we delete the fake stitch first, and then simulate it together.
This is also what I told you before, when I simulate to half, I will simulate the two layers that are related to each other, or the layer that is more likely to be unstable, and the layer that is newly added together.
Because we just added a new layer, the knot position is easy to be unstable, so we simulate it together to see if there is any instability.
In addition, in the process of simulation,
you can see this knot, let's take a closer look at it.
Will this knot cause it to shake and be unstable because of the squeeze of this piece?
Let's pause the simulation first, and then freeze this knot first.
Look, it's basically expanding slowly now.
Okay, grab this time and let it stop the simulation.
After the other parts are simulated,
wait for other versions.
Oh, it's slowly expanding.
It's pretty stable.
Activate it again, simulate it together, and simulate it with the seal of the outer layer to ensure that they are all stable.
Because we're going to change the action later.
Don't change the action before you activate all the versions and simulate them together.
So they have to calculate the change of action and calculate the conflict and squeeze of the inner and outer layers.
It will not be stable.
Understand?
Okay.
In addition, we freeze the seal and then calculate the outer layer separately.
This is my normal operation habit.
And then activate all the versions and simulate them together.
If you find this kind of penetration problem,
we will apply the layer of the entire version.
That is, the entire outer layer.
Then apply the layer of the seal.
Then remember to remove the conflict when you see an unstable button.
Okay, simulate it again.
Wait for it to simulate stability.
Okay.
Then rotate the view and then hide the outer layer.
Because sometimes it looks very stable on the surface.
In fact, because your computer is lagging,
so there is an unstable place inside it.
So everyone must remember.
Remember to hide the outer layer.
Take a look.
Take a look at the inner layer.
Is there any kind of penetration problem?
Unstable problem.
If not, we can continue to make further adjustments.
Return the layer to zero first.
Okay, and then the pants here.
Let's reduce the particle diameter of the pants first.
Because we are going to use a set of patterns later.
To fix these
So let's reduce the particle diameter first.
Okay, after reducing it,
find the brush function of the selection grid here.
In fact, it is a function near the selection grid function.
After selecting this function,
you can see that the selection is selected.
Select these wrinkles on the bottom.
Then right-click to select the shape optimization.
Then this part of the area will be selected.
After selecting,
we also have the cat's paw of the change action part.
Okay.
After that,
in order to prevent the change of the movement later,
in the process of changing the movement,
this is disassembled.
And everyone still remembers the position of the fold sleeve before.
Is it tight?
Easy to be unstable.
Then here,
we can prevent such a problem first.
Is to improve the friction coefficient of the fabric first.
Because when the friction coefficient of the fabric is increased,
this fabric is not easy to move relatively.
Just like you use glue to stick them together.
Can you make it up like this?
If you use glue to fix this piece of fabric,
it won't move together.
It's already stuck together.
If you change the movement again,
it won't come apart.
Understand?
Including this part of our sleeve,
it is the same.
Increase its friction coefficient a little.
Have you learned it?
Friction coefficient.
In fact,
whether it's a dress or a tie,
or we make a tie,
or gloves,
in short,
those you want it not to move or slide each other,
or moving panels,
you can improve its friction coefficient first before changing the movement.
Or if there is any shape that may be unstable,
you can improve the friction coefficient first.
Especially when you make a knot,
such as a butterfly knot,
or a scarf,
you can improve its friction coefficient,
so that it won't slide apart.
Okay.
After that,
let's put the outer layer of the clothing on it.
Just use the wind control device.
In the 3D window,
click on this environment setting like the earth.
There is a wind control device at the bottom.
Wait a minute.
Wind control device.
Display the wind control device.
After displaying it,
let's rotate the wind control device.
It will have a blue arrow.
This blue arrow is the direction of the wind blowing.
The direction of the wind blowing.
Take a closer look here.
There are two.
One is called spherical.
It's a spherical wind.
It's a four-sided wind.
There is another one called planar.
The planar is a fixed wind blowing.
If you don't understand what this means,
I have one here.
Take a good look.
First of all,
you can see that these two panels are in two directions.
Right?
Their faces are in two directions.
If I choose planar,
look at the wind.
Wind.
This direction.
I set the direction of the wind to be this direction.
It will only blow a parallel wind like this.
But if I choose spherical,
it is spherical.
See?
It will blow from the position where I blow the wind to the four sides.
If you use planar,
it will blow in one direction.
Parallel wind.
Parallel wind and spherical wind.
That's how you understand it.
So for our clothes,
we are definitely not blowing a spherical wind.
It's a parallel wind.
So here I put it.
This is the type that has been changed to planar.
Then you have to choose to activate it.
Then the intensity is lowered a little bit.
For example, it's 100.
Here I found that the wind of blowing 100 is not very responsive.
I will adjust the intensity to 1000.
After adjusting to 1000,
we can rotate it.
Adjust the direction of the wind blowing.
Then manually in the process of simulation.
In fact, because I have more panels,
there is another advantage.
That is, its reaction speed will be slower.
This gives me time to adjust.
After blowing the wind,
the position where my chin is.
When is it possible to use the spherical form?
There will be.
For example, you have to let,
that is,
that is, for example,
you have to let a structure
when the four sides and the eight sides are scattered.
time.
You will use the spherical wind.
Oops, I forgot what I was doing.
Then I lowered the intensity of the wind a little bit.
Then take a look.
It's almost the kind of dynamic effect I want.
I will turn off the wind control and no longer activate the wind.
Then turn on the wind control and turn on the wind control.
Let it be in the middle position, then pause the simulation.
Finally, let's take a look at the hat.
The hat is the one I used in the hat course before.
The fabric of the hat itself is relatively hard.
What is the use of part-shaped solidification?
Part-shaped solidification means that after you change the action,
this part of the fold will continue to be maintained.
Otherwise, it will cause the fabric to have different fold patterns due to the change in your action.
Or the fold of the part may dissipate.
If you want these folds to be preserved under any action,
you have to use solidification or part-shaped solidification.
Do you understand?
Let's continue to talk about the hat.
The characteristic of the hat is that it is reversed.
For example, the top part of the hat may be narrower,
and the whole hat will be larger.
The top and bottom of the hat are relatively large.
The top and bottom of the hat are reversed.
So we need to adjust the top and bottom of the hat.
First, change the fabric.
Because the previous fabric is too hard.
The previous fabric has a high bending strength.
Now we want to reduce the bending strength of the hat and the top of the hat.
So that it can be turned into a fabric that can retain some fold effect by manually dragging.
Secondly, we want to reduce its particle diameter.
Then manually drag the plate to the hat effect we want.
After that, we just need to make sure that the fabric is OK.
We can use fixed needles to control the hat effect later.
Then we change the circular structure of the top to oval.
Because most of the wool hats are oval.
Its top structure is oval.
After changing to an oval structure,
you will find that we have reduced the top plate.
The top plate is longer than the top plate.
So let's see the length.
Then change the length and shorten the upper side and the top plate.
After shortening, we freeze the top plate and the top plate.
Don't forget what I told you before.
Do we have to keep every corner straight?
Now that the top is short and the bottom is long.
Then do we have to turn this arc over?
See?
Now the corners are all 90 degrees or close to 90 degrees.
At this time, if you simulate it,
the position of its pin will not protrude.
Then we simulate the top plate activation together.
Then we can adjust its height and low position.
Click on the X button to create a straight line.
Then adjust these points.
See?
Because of the hat,
I observed that the front and back of the hat are relatively low.
Then the back and middle are also relatively low.
So let's adjust it manually.
After adjustment,
because the straight line is a protruding point,
it is not very smooth.
So we need to convert this straight line point into a curve point.
Or use the round curve curve tool to round it.
I will use the round curve curve tool to turn it.
After simulation,
I will drag some wrinkles out manually.
You can see that
because I have reduced the bending strength of these fabrics,
so the wrinkles now can be produced.
Otherwise,
otherwise its wrinkles,
in fact,
because sometimes people may feel a little useless,
the bending strength will also affect the wrinkle.
The bending strength will also affect the wrinkle.
Then how do they affect it?
I will talk about it briefly.
That is to say,
the bending strength is because
this plate is not easy to bend,
so it has a wrinkle.
It's just that it's not easy to bend,
so you can't see it,
because they are combined.
But,
the bending strength is not easy to produce a wrinkle,
because this fabric is not easy to stretch,
so in any operation that causes it to change,
for example,
you drag the plate,
there is a length difference between the inner and outer layers of the plate,
so when they are simulated,
the plate will move up and down.
In the process of these interactions,
its wrinkle will occur,
and once its wrinkle occurs,
it is not easy to dissipate.
So I will say that the wrinkle,
when I describe these two numbers,
I will say that
they all affect the production of this wrinkle,
because their production principle is different.
Forget it.
It doesn't matter.
Wake up.
You can watch my video
about physical properties.
Because the bending strength
affects whether the fabric is easy to bend.
The higher the bending strength,
the more the fabric is not easy to bend,
so it is not easy to form a very fine wrinkle.
The strength of the wrinkle
affects whether it can be stretched.
For example,
like a balloon,
it is easy to stretch.
Because you can blow the balloon,
blow the air,
it will inflate very strongly.
But for example,
like a fan cloth,
you can't pull it.
There is no dead end.
I just didn't put the video.
OK.
Then freeze.
After freezing,
activate the hat plate.
Adjust its width on both sides.
And the point of the front and back.
Move it.
OK.
In fact,
because the bending strength of the hat is too high,
it is not easy to make some bending effects.
So we reduce the bending strength a little bit.
At this time,
I freeze the hat.
the other parts of the version are because
I have roughly used my hand
to drag out some creases.
I don't want these creases
to disappear because of the natural simulation.
So I freeze it first.
It doesn't matter.
About the material physics,
I will explain it to you later.
OK.
Use a sewing needle to make this bend effect.
Then use the editing sewing tool
to delete these two sewing needles.
Then press the control key to start the simulation.
Wait until they are half simulated.
Pause the simulation.
Then the frozen version is ready.
OK.
Then we use the original curve tool
to smooth out these straight lines.
OK.
After that,
there are these bullets.
First of all,
these bullets are made of cloth
in MD,
and then they are poured out in the form of OBJ.
Then,
when I pour this OBJ in,
I choose to pour it in as a copy.
After pouring it in as a copy,
as long as you don't put this copy
on the board
with glue,
then the copy itself can have a conflict.
You can click on its conflict thickness on the right.
OK.
First, put this bullet in the right place.
Then right-click and choose to remove.
This will remove the bond between the copy and the board.
Let the copy stand out.
After the copy stands out,
you can set the conflict thickness.
This way it can affect
the other boards around it.
It's a bit like a virtual model,
but it's a virtual model that is more convenient and quick to use.
Then simulate it with the control key.
It will hold up the other boards.
Oh, this is almost
the content related to this issue of Niu Cai Fu.
As for the physical properties of the material,
you can click on our homepage.
There is a tutorial video I made before.
In fact, it is more clear.
Floating indefinitely.
I was just showing it.
There are many other videos.
If you don't like it,
you can go to the blog.
The link is in the description.
I hope you find it useful.
Thank you.
You can see that I can use the same method
to create the same thing as before.
It's the same method.
Then we'll see you next time.
Bye.